HEATHER LORENZO

heatherlorenzo.com

email: heather@heatherlorenzo.com

phone: 347-612-3886 location: Queens, NY

SUMMARY

I am a web developer, formally trained in design, who loves making web applications with the user always in mind. To me, UX is a form of storytelling, beginning with easy to use functionality, enhancing that experience through its visual design, then growing it into an app with use and purpose. I'm always ready to discover new and different ways to tackle a problem and love learning new technologies that help me grow as a developer.

SKILLS

Front End: CSS, Javascript, jQuery, AJAX, HTML, Bootstrap

Back End: Ruby, Rails, Sinatra, Active Record

Databases: PostgreSQL, SQLite

Testing: Rspec, CircleCl, SimpleCov, Jasmin, Capybara

Currently Learning: PHP, Laravel, Sass

PROJECTS

There's a Board github.com/theresaboard/theres-a-board

Core Developer of There's a Board, an internal app to encourage and aid Dev Bootcamp students to tutor and study by scheduling their time, providing goals to tutor a number of times and promote friendly competition between students on the number of times they tutored. This is an internal app for Dev Bootcamp students and is currently being adapted for use at the NYC campus.

- Implemented the jQuery plug-in fullCalendar to neatly display scheduling information to our users.
- Built our own front-end using Javascript to allow users to interact with our site.
- Built the back-end using Rails and the Rails API to create and update appointments.
- Used Bootstrap theme for a clean and unified style throughout the site.
- Continuous deployment using Heroku

To watch a demo of the project visit: https://vimeo.com/145595148

Stack Overphil stack-overphil.herokuapp.com

Created a version of Stack Overflow that allowed our users to ask questions, answer questions, and decide on which answer was the best for their question. Users can vote on any question, answer or comment. A user can also sort this information by popularity, recently posted or by tags.

- Built our back-end using Ruby on Rails, to create questions, answers and comments and their corresponding relationships.
- We implemented AJAX for quick filtering and searching for questions.
- I used plain CSS for the styling of the site

EXPERIENCE

Mentor at Dev Bootcamp

Nov. 2015 - Present

- Help current students who have questions on the day's challenges
- Review student code and offer suggestions for improvement
- Teach short lectures on subjects which students need supplemental help.

Lead Designer at Dadada Media Group

June 2009 - August 2015

- Developing marketing campaigns and strategies for our clients using print, radio and television media platforms.
- Storyboarding for television commercials
- Shooting green screen footage
- Video editing and color correction of raw footage
- Video compositing and 2D animation using After Effects
- 3D modeling and animation using Cinema 4D
- Print design for magazines, newspapers and online advertising

Design Software: Photoshop, Illustrator, InDesign, After Effects, Cinema 4D, Final Cut Pro

Freelance Artist for Docere Medical Spa

June 2009 - November 2009

- Created digital paintings of botanicals and fruit for their facility using Photoshop, which were printed using giclee ink and archival paper
- Logo design

Intern at Dadada Media Group

June-Sept 2008

- Studied the ins and outs of a full-service advertising agency
- Created print and static online advertisements for magazines and newspapers
- Helped out on set of video shoots

EDUCATION

Dev Bootcamp July - November 2015

Cleveland Institute of Art 2009

Bachelor of Fine Arts Majoring in Digital Art

OTHER INTERESTS

In my free time I enjoy cooking and improving my chicken pot pie recipe. I play strategy games like Civilization, and keep busy with DIY projects and anything crafty. I love animals, I have one giant cat and one tiny dog; they get along quite well. For almost a year on Monday evenings I've been learning how to tango. It is a hard dance to learn, but so much fun and hopefully I will be demonstrating my skills in a student showcase soon!